Guide to the Emil J. Dillon Papers, ca. 1873-1933
Department of Special Collections
Emil J. Dillon Papers,
ca. 1873-1933
M0935
Dillon, Emil Joseph, 1854-1933
80 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Correspondence with statesmen, historians, staff of the Daily Telegraph, family, etc., memoranda, diaries, subject files, articles, materials on Oriental studies, books and journals, and photographs.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions on access.
Acquisition Information
Purchased, 1997.
Biography
An academic (Professor of Philology at University of Kharkov, authority on oriental languages, ancient Armenian and Sanskrit), Dillon was best known as a foreign correspondent for London's Daily Telegraph from 1886 unti well after the 1914-1918 war. He was considered a "semi-official ambassador", and wrote frequently on foreign affairs in CONTEMPORY REVIEW and other leading magazines and journals. He traveled widely and covered such major events as the Boxer Rebellion in China, the Russo-Japanese War, the Balkan wars, Mexico, and the Dreyfus case. He was considered particularly an expert on Russia, and was the confidential adviser to Count Witte, the Russian Minister and Prime Minister.
Collection Scope and Content Summary
Correspondence with statesmen, historians, staff of the Daily Telegraph, family, etc., memoranda, diaries, subject files, articles, materials on Oriental studies, books and journals, and photographs.
Access Terms
Daily Telegraph (London, England); Diplomacy--Great Britain.; Foreign correspondents.; Journalism.; Witte, Count, 1849-1915.
Collection Contents
- Series 1. Correspondence
  - Subseries 1. Letters, Telegrams, and Related Notes
    - Aalberg, Ida1891 Sept. 20 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      In French.
    - Aberdeen [?]1914 Oct. 28 - Nov. 19; n.y., Incl. a descriptive list, tls (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Contains correspondence relating to Sir James Dougherty; Mr. Justice Wylie, Judge; Dr, Michael Cox; Mrs. Cox; Lady Aberdeen; Mr. Moreton Frewen.
    - Adashidze - Gorlenko, [?], Princessn.d., Incl. a descriptive list (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Adler, Victor, Dr.1902 Dec. 16 - 1903 Jan. 31, Incl. a descriptive list, a press cutting (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Contains correspondence relating to Czar Alexander III; Kaiser Wilhelm II; Herr Rebel.
    - Aehrenthal, Alois Freiherr [?], von, Baron [1 of 2]1909 March 18 - March 31; n.d., Incl. tls, als, a press cutting (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Some materials are in German and French.
    - Aehrenthal, Alois Freiherr [?], von, Baron [2 of 2]1909 Sept. 13; n.d., Incl. tls, als, a press cutting (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Agakhan [?]1917 Dec. 2 - 1930 Oct. 14, Incl. tls (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Contains correspondence to Mrs. Dillon.
    - Aguirre, Amado1923 March 19, Incl. a descriptive list, tls (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Contains correspondence in Spanish relating to Sr. D. Luis Castillo Ledón.
    - Aidan, D.M.1890 Nov. 9, Incl. a descriptive list (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Aivazovskii, Ivan [1 of 2]1899 March [?] 22 - 1939 June 8, Incl. a descriptive list, tls, a postcard, inventories (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Contains materials relating to Klever; Mr. Laws. Some materials are in Russian.
      Aivazoffsky, Ivan; Aivasowsky, Ivan.
    - Aivazovskii, Ivan [2 of 2]1960 Jan. 15; n.d., Incl. a descriptive list, tls, a postcard, inventories (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Akimov, Mikhail Grigorievich1910 Feb. 19 / March 4 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      In Russian.
    - Albeniz, Adriana, De [1 of 2]1937 - 1939 March 29; n.d., Incl. a descriptive list, a press cutting, leaflets. (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Contains materials relating to General Franco; Marquesa del Moral.
    - Albeniz, Adriana, De [2 of 2]1939 March 12 - April 26, Incl. a descriptive list, a press cutting, leaflets. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Alexander III [1 of 6]1894 Oct. 12 - Oct. 16, Incl. a descriptive list, bulletins, typescripts, manuscripts. (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Some materials are in Russian.
      Aleksandr III
    - Alexander III [2 of 6]1894 Oct. 29; n.d., Incl. a descriptive list, bulletins, typescripts, manuscripts. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Alexander III [3 of 6]1894 Oct. 31 - Nov. 6, Incl. a descriptive list, bulletins, typescripts, manuscripts. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Alexander III [4 of 6]1894 Oct. 31 - Nov. 20, Incl. a descriptive list, bulletins, typescripts, manuscripts. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Alexander III [5 of 6]1894 Nov. 1 - Nov. 15; n.d., Incl. a descriptive list, bulletins, typescripts, manuscripts. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Alexander III [6 of 6]1894; n.d. / n.y., Incl. a descriptive list, bulletins, typescripts, manuscripts. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Anannoff, Alexandr 1895 Jan. [?] - May 10 [?] (Box 1, Folder 21)
      Anannoff, Aleksandr
    - Ancester [?], [?], Lord & Lady 1917 June 14 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Andreades, A. 1914 [?] Dec. 30 - 1915 Jan. 3 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - D'Annunzio, Gabriéle 1915 March 2; n.d. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Apponyi, Albert, Count [1 of 3]1892 August 16 - 1894 [?] June 2; n.d., Incl. a press cutting, a typescript. (Box 1, Folder 25)
      Appony, Albert
    - Apponyi, Albert, Count [2 of 3]1908 [?] - 1909 Sept. 27; n.d., Incl. a press cutting, a typescript. (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Apponyi, Albert, Count [3 of 3]n.d., Incl. a press cutting, a typescript. (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Arakelian, A.1895 [?]; n.d., Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Arens, Zh.1928 Sept. 13, Tls. (Box 1, Folder 29)
      Contains correspondence in Russian to Ianson.
    - Armour, Norman1947 July 3 - Oct. 6; n.d. / n.y., Incl. tls and press cuttings. (Box 1, Folder 30)
      Contains materials relating to President Roosevelt; Princess Myra Kaudacheff; Mr. Braden.
    - Arnott, John1914 Oct. [?] 26 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Astor, Ada, Lady[n.y.] May 11 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Athristan-Johnson, W.[n.y.] April 16 - 1919 May 21, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Attendge, A. Hillard1892 Feb. 15, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Baddley, J.F.n.d. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Baerlein, Henry, Esq. [1 of 7]1890 Oct. 6 - 1905 Dec. 16, Incl. a descriptive list, postcards, tls, a press cutting. (Box 2, Folder 6)
      Contains materials relating to Brewer; Mrs. Walker; Mr. Heckscher; Justizrath Wolf; Heineman; Dent; MacMillan; Peters; Horace; Abu'l-ala; Omar Khayyam; Constantine Dillon; Galouste Gulbenkian; Hughes Massey; Lord Burnham; M.H. Gill; Bishop Bessak Toumayan.
    - Baerlein, Henry, Esq. [2 of 7]1908 April 28 - May 7; n.d., Incl. a descriptive list, postcards, tls, a press cutting. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Baerlein, Henry, Esq. [3 of 7]1908 July 26 - 1910 Nov. 24, Incl. a descriptive list, postcards, tls, a press cutting. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Baerlein, Henry, Esq. [4 of 7]1911 Nov. 24 - 1912 Dec. 14; n.d. / n.y., Incl. a descriptive list, postcards, tls, a press cutting. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Baerlein, Henry, Esq. [5 of 7]1945 April 11 - 1949 Nov. 19, Incl. a descriptive list, postcards, tls, a press cutting. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Baerlein, Henry, Esq. [6 of 7]1950 Dec. 6 - 1957 August 10, Incl. a descriptive list, postcards, tls, a press cutting. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Baerlein, Henry, Esq. [7 of 7]1959 Jan. 6 - 1960 Jan. 20 [?], Incl. a descriptive list, postcards, tls, a press cutting. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Baernreither, [?]1913 May 8 [?] (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Baird, John, M.P.1915 Jan. 6 - 1916 Jan. 19, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Bakhmeteff, B., G [eneral ?]1909 - 1919 July 1; n.d. / n.y., Incl. typescripts. (Box 2, Folder 15)
      Contains materials relating to Oscar Crosby; Capt. Finzi; Bratiano; the Roumanian Premier; President Wilson; Stsherbatcheff; Koltchak; Denikin.
      Bauhmeteff, B., G [eneral ?]
    - Balagie, Ramchandre, of Bithour, Prince [1 of 2]1896 Feb. 7 [?]; n.d., Incl. a descriptive list, a typescript, a press cutting. (Box 2, Folder 16)
      A press cutting is in Russian.
    - Balagie, Ramchandre, of Bithour, Prince [2 of 2]18 [79 June 13 / 96 May 17 ?], Incl. a descriptive list, a typescript, a press cutting. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Balfour, Arthur J. [1 of 3]1893 Ju [ne / ly ?] 21 - 1894 Jan. 30, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 2, Folder 18)
      Contains materials relating to Bismarck; Cavour; Maxim Gorkii; Wagner.
    - Balfour, Arthur J. [2 of 3]1902 July 16 - August 4, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Balfour, Arthur J. [3 of 3]1902 July 30 - 1916 Feb. 12, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Barclay, Thomas, Sir1931 August [n.d.] - Oct. 3, Incl. tls, a press cutting, a memorandum. (Box 2, Folder 21)
      Contains materials relating to John Woodman O.B.E.; Mrs. Dillon.
    - Barker, J. Ellis1922 July 24, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 2, Folder 22)
      Contains materials relating to Clarke; Moreau de Jonnes; Rosny; Mrs. Dillon.
    - Barlow, Basil1915 August 16, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Barneville, Maurice F., De1917 July 14 - 1920 Dec. 28, Incl. postcards. (Box 2, Folder 24)
      Contains correspondence to Constantine Dillon.
    - Baroda, Gaekwar, Maharaja1924 Ju [ne / ly ?] 25 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Barrère, L.[n.y.] April 23 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Barron, Clarence W.1906 April 28 - 1927 June 16; n.d., Incl. tls, a reprint, a card. (Box 2, Folder 27)
      Contains materials relating to Count Witte; J. Pi-Suñer; Mr. Hugh Bancroft; Mrs. Dillon; Miss Vareschina.
    - Bartlett [?], E. Ashmead n.d., Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Bashmakoff, Aleksandr A. [1 of 6]1879 Nov. 25 - 1884 Dec. 13, Incl. a descriptive list, postcards. (Box 2, Folder 29)
      In French and Russian.
      Baschmakoff, Alexandre A.
    - Bashmakoff, Aleksandr A. [2 of 6]1885 Sept. 16 - 1888 Nov. 21, Incl. a descriptive list, postcards. (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Bashmakoff, Aleksandr A. [3 of 6]1889 Feb. 3 - April 29, Incl. a descriptive list, postcards. (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Bashmakoff, Aleksandr A. [4 of 6]1889 Oct. 19 - 1890 Nov. 8, Incl. a descriptive list, postcards. (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Bashmakoff, Aleksandr A. [5 of 6]1919 June 7 - 1927 August [?] 16, Incl. a descriptive list, postcards. (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Bashmakoff, Aleksandr A. [6 of 6]1927 Sept. 16 - Dec. 31; n.d. / n.y., Incl. a descriptive list, postcards. (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Basilesco, N.1919 May 15 - July 16; n.y., Incl. tls, a typescript. (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Some materials are in French.
      Basilescu, N.
    - Batcheff, [?]1908 March 2 / 15 - 1909 [?] Nov. [?] 14 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Batscheff, [?]
    - Bathurst, Arthur M.1917 Sept. 27 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Battersby, H.F.P. [1 of 15]1886 April 18 - 1887 May 21, Incl. a descriptive list, postcards. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Battersby, H.F.P. [2 of 15]1887 August 1 - 1888 Dec. 14, Incl. a descriptive list, postcards. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Battersby, H.F.P. [3 of 15]1889 Feb. 15 - Nov. 15, Incl. a descriptive list, postcards. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Battersby, H.F.P. [4 of 15]1889 Nov. 28 - 1890 March 19, Incl. a descriptive list, postcards. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Battersby, H.F.P. [5 of 15]1890 April 8 - July 4, Incl. a descriptive list, postcards. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Battersby, H.F.P. [6 of 15]1890 July 19 - Oct. 16, Incl. a descriptive list, postcards. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Battersby, H.F.P. [7 of 15]1890 Oct. 30 - 1891 May 23, Incl. a descriptive list, postcards. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Battersby, H.F.P. [8 of 15]1891 August 17 - Oct. 13, Incl. a descriptive list, postcards. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Battersby, H.F.P. [9 of 15]1891 Nov. 8 - Nov. 27, Incl. a descriptive list, postcards. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Battersby, H.F.P. [10 of 15]1891 Dec. 8 - 1892 Jan. 14, Incl. a descriptive list, postcards. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Battersby, H.F.P. [11 of 15]1892 Jan. 22 - April 19, Incl. a descriptive list, postcards. (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Battersby, H.F.P. [12 of 15]1892 Sept. 1 - 1893 March 30, Incl. a descriptive list, postcards. (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Battersby, H.F.P. [13 of 15]1893 Nov. 25 - 1894 Dec. 7, Incl. a descriptive list, postcards. (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Battersby, H.F.P. [14 of 15]1897 Oct. 31 - 1925 July 1; n.d., Incl. a descriptive list, postcards. (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Battersby, H.F.P. [15 of 15]n.d. / n.y., Incl. a descriptive list, postcards. (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Bell, C. Moberly1891 Jan. 6 - April 18, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Bellegarde, Sophia, De1914 Feb [n.d.], Incl. a descriptive list, a manuscript (a short story). (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Belloc, H.1925 Oct. 28, Tls. (Box 3, Folder 21)
      Contains materials relating to Mrs. Dillon; Madame Suqué; Maria Teresa.
    - Benes, E. [?]1919 May 26 (Box 3, Folder 22)
      Benets [?], E. [?]
    - Bentley, Bede John Francis, Captain1914 [?] August 2 - 1939 July 18; n.d., Incl. press cuttings. (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Berchtold, Leopold, Count [1 of 6]1907 Feb. 15 - 1908 Jan. 18 / 31; n.d., Incl. a descriptive list, postcards, als [?]. (Box 3, Folder 24)
      Contains materials relating to Count Westphalen; Louis Berchtold; Hoyos. Some materials are in German.
    - Berchtold, Leopold, Count [2 of 6]1909 [month?] 27 - May 6, Incl. a descriptive list, postcards, als [?]. (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Berchtold, Leopold, Count [3 of 6]1909 May 1 / 14 - Dec. 9 / 22, Incl. a descriptive list, postcards, als [?]. (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Berchtold, Leopold, Count [4 of 6]1910 Jan. 9 - 1912 Nov. 24, Incl. a descriptive list, postcards, als [?]. (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Berchtold, Leopold, Count [5 of 6]1912 Nov. 26 - 1914 July 22, Incl. a descriptive list, postcards, als [?]. (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Berchtold, Leopold, Count [6 of 6]1914 July 24; n.d. / n.y., Incl. a descriptive list, postcards, als [?]. (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Berlin, Isiah1960 Oct. 28 - Nov. 7, Tls. (Box 4, Folder 1)
      Contains materials relating to Constantine Dillon; Count Leo Tolstoi; Kraus; Mrs. Myers; Baerlein; Curtis Brown; Witte; Mr. John Carter; Mr. J. Simmons.
    - Berridge, Albert J.n.d. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Berthelot, [?].1916 Nov. 9 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Bessonova, Raisa V.1928 June 3 - 1933 Feb. 4, Incl. a descriptive list, postcards. (Box 4, Folder 4)
      Contains correspondence in Russian to Constantine DIllon.
    - Bickell, G., Prof.1893 May 14 - 1899 Dec. 24, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 4, Folder 5)
      Contains materials relating to Rev. F. Bogka; Mgr. d'Hulst.
    - Bilibin, Ivan Iakovlevich1921 May 22; n.d. (Box 4, Folder 6)
      Bilibine, Ivan Iakovlevich
    - Billington, M.F.1910 May 22 - May 23, Incl. a press cutting. (Box 4, Folder 7)
      Contains materials relating to King Edward.
    - Bistram, Rodrigue, De, Baron1929 Oct. 24 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Blackwell, Alice Stone1905 August 18, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Blanchford [?], W.1901 March 22 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Bland, J.P.1901 Jan. 19 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Bloch, John, Dr. [1 of 3]1900 Feb. 12 - Feb. 14, Incl. a descriptive list, a press cutting. (Box 4, Folder 12)
      Contains materials relating to Madame Emilie de Bloch. Some materials are in French and Russian.
    - Bloch, John, Dr. [2 of 3]1900 Feb. 7 / 19 - 1901 Sept. 5, Incl. a descriptive list, a press cutting. (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Bloch, John, Dr. [3 of 3]1902 Jan. - Feb. [n.d.], Incl. a descriptive list, a press cutting. (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Blunt, Wilfrid S.1919 April 30 - May 29 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Bolotoff, Sergei, De.191 [8 / 9 ?] May 30 - 1924 May 4 / 17, Incl. a descriptive list, press cuttings. (Box 4, Folder 16)
      Contains materials relating to Prince Viazemskii; Prince Vladimir Viazemskii. Some materials are in Russian.
      Bolotoff, Serge, De.
    - Bompard, M. [1 of 4]1906 June 26 / July 9 - 1908 Jan. 31 / Feb. 13; n.y., Incl. press cuttings, als [?], a typescript. (Box 4, Folder 17)
      Contains materials relating to Izwolskii; Dubrovin; Pourishkevich; Urusov; Brianchaninoff; the Tsar. Some materials are in French and Russian.
    - Bompard, M. [2 of 4]1910 June 19 [?] - 1911 March 27, Incl. press cuttings, als [?], a typescript. (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Bompard, M. [3 of 4]1911 Nov. 28 - 1912 [?], Incl. press cuttings, als [?], a typescript. (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Bompard, M. [4 of 4]1912 June 5 - July 13, Incl. press cuttings, als [?], a typescript. (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Bonaventura, Fr.1871 July [?] 2 - 1874 August 9, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 4, Folder 21)
      Some materials are in Italian.
    - Borisoff, Aleksandr.[n.y.] March [?] 26 / April 8 - March [?] 27 / April 9, Incl. a descriptive list, a typescript. (Box 4, Folder 22)
      Contains materials relating to President Roosevelt; Mr. Morgan; Count Witte.
      Borisov, Alexander; Borissoff, Alexander.
    - Bormans, A.1885 [?] [month ?] 13 - Oct. 15, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Borse, Edith[n.y.] June 2 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Boulton, [?]1922 Feb. 21 - April 20, Incl. a descriptive list, als [?]. (Box 4, Folder 25)
      Contains materials relating to Pilsudski; Lenin; Baron Ago Von Maltzan.
    - Brailsford, H.N.[n.y.] June 23, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Briand, Aristide1916 [?] Sept. 27, Incl. a card. (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Briason, Noel[n.y.] July 20 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Brocklehurst, John1906 Feb. 16 - 1914 Nov. 21, Incl. a descriptive list, a leaflet. (Box 4, Folder 29)
      Contains materials relating to Teodore P. Brocklehurst.
    - Brooks, Sydney1912 Dec. 19 (Box 4, Folder 30)
      Contains materials relating to Boris Lebedeff; Leveson Gower (qv).
    - Brown, Curtis, Esq. [1 of 6]1918 March 12 - 1919 Feb. 19, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 4, Folder 31)
      Contains materials relating to A.H.Dakers; Kerenskii; Korniloff; Lloyd George; President Wilson; Sir George Hutchinson; Mr. Brainard; Countess Witte; Count Witte; Lord Jellicoe; Count Czernin; Clemencean; Foch; Mark Henri; Von Tirpitz; M. Izwolskii; Mr. French Strother.
    - Brown, Curtis, Esq. [2 of 6]1919 Feb. 24 - April 8, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Brown, Curtis, Esq. [3 of 6]1919 April 10 - May 20, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Brown, Curtis, Esq. [4 of 6]1919 May 22 - June 2; n.d., Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Brown, Curtis, Esq. [5 of 6]1919 June 3 - July 1, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Brown, Curtis, Esq. [6 of 6]1919 July 4 - July 28, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Buchanan, George W. [1 of 2]1908 [?] Dec. 20 - 1910 August 31; n.d., Incl. a descriptive list, als [?]. (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Buchanan, George W. [2 of 2]1913 April 24 - May 1; n.d., Incl. a descriptive list, als [?]. (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Buckmaster, [?], Lord1917 March [?] 8 [?] (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Bunting, Percy William [1 of 7]1891 [?] Oct. 31 - 1892 April 4; n.y., Incl. a descriptive list, tls, als, an obituary. (Box 5, Folder 2)
      Contains materials relating to the Pope; Mr. Canton; Brandi; the Kaiser; Lady Bunting; Evelyn M. Bunting; Sheldon [?] Bunting.
    - Bunting, Percy William [2 of 7]1893 April 25 - 1895 May 1, Incl. a descriptive list, tls, als, an obituary. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Bunting, Percy William [3 of 7]1895 June 7 - 1902 June 17; n.d., Incl. a descriptive list, tls, als, an obituary. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Bunting, Percy William [4 of 7]1902 Oct. 21 - 1912 May 25, Incl. a descriptive list, tls, als, an obituary. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Bunting, Percy William [5 of 7]1914 Oct. 30 - 1917 Jan. 29, Incl. a descriptive list, tls, als, an obituary. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Bunting, Percy William [6 of 7]1915 July 27 - 1917 Feb. 21; n.y., Incl. a descriptive list, tls, als, an obituary. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Bunting, Percy William [7 of 7]1919 Oct. 22; n.d., Incl. a descriptive list, tls, als, an obituary. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Burleigh, Bennet1908 Nov. 23, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Burnham, [?]1917 May 7, Tls. (Box 5, Folder 10)
      Contains materials relating to Le Sage; Ashmead-Bartlett; Harold Williams.
    - Bustany, Al [?] [1 of 3]1912 April 1 - July 7, Incl. a descriptive list, a typescript. (Box 5, Folder 11)
      Boustany, Al [?]
    - Bustany, Al [?] [2 of 3]1913 Jan. 26 - March 31; n.d., Incl. a descriptive list, a typescript. (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Bustany, Al [?] [3 of 3]1913 April 26 - 1914 July 13, Incl. a descriptive list, a typescript. (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Caillaux, Joseph [1 of 4]1916 August 10 - August 28, Incl. a descriptive list, tls, a postcard. (Box 5, Folder 14)
      Contains materials relating to Lord Northcliff. In French.
    - Caillaux, Joseph [2 of 4]1916 Oct. 17 - Dec. 1; n.y., Incl. a descriptive list, tls, a postcard. (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Caillaux, Joseph [3 of 4]1922 June 19 - 1933 Jan. 30, Incl. a descriptive list, tls, a postcard. (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Caillaux, Joseph [4 of 4]n.d., Incl. a descriptive list, tls, a postcard. (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Canals, Salvador1924 Sept. 27; n.d. [1924 Oct. 5 ?], Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Carey [?], W.D., Major General1894 Feb. 4 - Feb. 16, Incl. a postcard. (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Carrington, [?], Lord1894 Dec. 15 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      Contains materials relating to Lord Chamberlain.
    - Cartwright, Fairfaxn.d., Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Castellane, Marquis Boni, De [1 of 3]1915 Dec. 28 - 1916 July 23, Incl. a press cutting, tls, a typescript. (Box 5, Folder 22)
      Contains materials relating to Mr. Hughes; Mr. de l'Oncle; Miss Anna Gould. Some materials are in French.
    - Castellane, Marquis Boni, De [2 of 3]1917 March 5 - Sept. 27, Incl. a press cutting, tls, a typescript. (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Castellane, Marquis Boni, De [3 of 3]1919 April 2 - 1929 Feb. 19, Incl. a press cutting, tls, a typescript. (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Cauwelaerd [?], Fram [?], Van1911 April [?] 15, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Cecil, Robert, Lord [1 of 3]1916 Jan. 19 - Feb. 2, Incl. tls. (Box 5, Folder 26)
      Contains materials relating to Lord Burnham; Sir George Buchanan; Mr. Vansittart; Mr. Kyhlberg.
    - Cecil, Robert, Lord [2 of 3]1916 Feb. 16 - May 31, Incl. tls. (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Cecil, Robert, Lord [3 of 3]1916 July 10 - 1917 June 2, Incl. tls. (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Chamberlain [?], Austen [?]1893 June 28 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Changouni, Vahram Evêque, Bishop1911 Oct. 8 / 21, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Chapman & Hall, Limited [1 of 2]1891 April 20 - 1916 June 13, Incl. tls. (Box 6, Folder 3)
      Contains materials relating to W.L.Courtney; Harry Lawson; Mr. E.F.Wise, Esq.; Mr. Arthur Waugh, Esq.; Mr. A.H. [?] Dakers.
    - Chapman & Hall, Limited [2 of 2]1916 July 11 - 1917 April 17, Incl. tls. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Charency, H., De, Comte1879 June 13 - 1885 Oct. 22, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 6, Folder 5)
      One letter is in French.
    - Charykhov, Ivan Sergeevich1890 [month ?] 5 / 17 [?] - 1906 Oct. 6 [?] (Box 6, Folder 6)
      Contains correspondence relating to Elena Charykhova; Anna Chirikova; Tolstoi; Dashkoff; Kuzminskii; Wolkenstein [?]. Some materials are in Russian.
      Cherechoff, Ivan Sergeevich
    - Cheradame [?], André1916 August 7, Tls. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Cherif Pasha, General [1 of 7]1911 August [?] 8 - 1927 [?] Nov. 28, Incl. tls, offprints, a declaration. (Box 6, Folder 8)
      Contains materials relating to Ahmed Moukhtas Pasha; Kiámil Pasha; Colonel Sadik Bey; Ismaïl Kémal Bey; Hodja Kadri Effendi; Nazim Pasha; Sabah Eddine; Grand Vizier; Memduck Bey; Madame Dillon; Bastri Bey; Moustafa Sabri Effendi. Some materials are in French.